neomed.edu 2019-08-08

# Privacy Statement | Northeast Ohio Medical University | NEOMED

## Online Privacy Statement

At Northeast Ohio Medical University (“NEOMED”, “University”, “we”, “our”, or “us”), we are committed to protecting the privacy of website visitors. This Privacy Statement applies to the information we collect and store when you visit our website and describes how we utilize and protect this information. Contact information can be found at the end of this Privacy Statement.

### What information is collected?

It is important to us that you are aware of the types of information we collect. When you access or use our website, we automatically collect and store the following aggregated information about your visit to make improvements to our website:

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you access our website;
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our website;
  * The date and time you access our website;
  * The pages, files, documents, and links that you visit; and
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked to this website.

Additionally, our website will only collect personal information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide to us (e.g., by sending emails, completing Web-based forms, or responding to surveys).

Finally, some sections of our website use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies (see “Cookie Notice” below) to help us analyze how visitors use our website. For more information on how Google collects and processes this data, please visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> and for more information on their privacy practices, please visit <https://privacy.google.com/>.

### From where do we receive personal data?

NEOMED receives personal data from multiple sources, most often directly from you or under your direction who has provided it to a third party (e.g., application for admission to NEOMED).

### How is this information used?

We collect website visitor information to optimize visitor experiences, manage visitor relationships with NEOMED, identify issues and errors, conduct market research, promote further communications, gauge communication effectiveness, and gain insights into user behavior and preferences.

NEOMED does not sell or rent website visitor information and does not share website visitor information except as compelled by law. We comply with all laws that prohibit the release of information and that limit the type of information shared. This includes, but is not limited to, student education records protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”), credit card information protected by the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard, and consumer information protected by the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act.

We will only share information about you with other parties when one or more of the following conditions apply:

  * We have your consent to share the information;
  * We need to share your information to provide the service or product you requested;
  * We need to send your information to third parties who work on behalf of NEOMED to provide a service or product to you;
  * The information in question is considered directory information consistent with FERPA regulations;
  * We need to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or requests through the Ohio Public Records Act, or any other legal process; or
  * We find it necessary to protect or defend the legal rights and/or property of NEOMED.

As mentioned, we do not release personal student information, other than directory information, to other parties except in limited circumstances. Student directory information may be released without the student’s written consent. If students do not want their directory information released, a student may request in writing that it not be released and file the request with the Office of the Registrar. For more information on FERPA at NEOMED, please visit <https://www.neomed.edu/registrar/ferpa/>.

### Our commitment to the privacy of children

NEOMED does not knowingly collect website visitor information from children as defined by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

### Cookie Notice

A cookie is a piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser in response to a requested resource, in which the web browser could store temporarily and return to the server on any subsequent visits or requests. Cookies are often used to remember information about preferences and pages you have visited and can carry all or parts of the information stored to other websites that the user may visit or to third parties. A third-party service such as YouTube, Twitter, Google Analytics, and Facebook may set cookies, which NEOMED has incorporated into its website. Information on each of these platforms’ cookie policies can be found on each respective site.

These cookies may stay on your browser into the future until they expire, or you delete them. Some of these cookies are erased when you close your browser window, and some persist for a period of time, depending on your browser and computer settings. Further general information about cookies and how they work is available at the Federal Trade Commission Consumer Information website (<https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0042-online-tracking#understanding_cookies>).

#### Types of cookies

  * A **third-party cookie** is placed by a domain other than that of the website the user is visiting.
  * A **session cookie** is temporary, linking the actions of a user during the any given browser session. When the browser is closed, the cookie is deleted.
  * A **persistent cookie** , also known as a permanent cookie, is stored for a specific period of time and activates each time the user visits the website that created the cookie.

#### Use of cookies

NEOMED uses third-party, session, and persistent cookies and similar technology to collect aggregated information of our visitors to some of our website regarding your use and to help us remember you and your preferences when you revisit our website. No personally identifiable information is collected through cookies.

We may allow selected third parties to place cookies through the website to provide us with better insights into the use of our website. These third parties may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when using our website.

### Information Security

Wherever your personal information may be held within NEOMED or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect and secure the information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure. Our Information Security Policy and corresponding Information Technology policies can be found at <https://www.neomed.edu/policies/by-category/#it>.

### Encryption

NEOMED uses encryption to prevent unauthorized parties from accessing Restricted Data (information protected by federal, state or local laws and/or regulations). You are normally required to enter a NEOMED username and password (“credentials”) when you request data about yourself or to ensure that you are a member of the University community. For example, students who want to check their grades or staff members who complete time sheets must enter their NEOMED credentials, so the system knows who is requesting the data. This login process uses Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) so credentials are encrypted between the Web browser and the Web server. Additionally, our authorized third parties facilitate encrypted transactions that enable you to pay for products or services online with a credit card; NEOMED does not collect or maintain credit card information.

### External Linking

NEOMED’s website may contain links to external websites, not owned by, or officially affiliated with NEOMED in any way. When navigating to external websites, you leave NEOMED’s website and are no longer subject to our Privacy Statement. NEOMED is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-NEOMED website, and such links are not intended to be an endorsement of those website or their content.

### Data Retention

In accordance with our Records Retention Schedule (<https://www.neomed.edu/generalcounsel/records-retention/>)[,](https://www.neomed.edu/generalcounsel/records-retention/) NEOMED keeps your information for as long as needed to fulfill the particular purpose for which it was collected. We may also retain your records if legally required.

### Disclaimer of Liability

The information contained in this Privacy Statement explains the practices that NEOMED has adopted for its website. In legal terms, it shall not be construed as a contractual promise, and the University reserves the right to amend it at any time. Neither NEOMED nor any of its units, departments, programs, employees, agents, or individual trustees shall be held liable for any improper or incorrect use of the information described and/or contained on our website and assumes no responsibility for anyone’s use of the information.

### Changes to Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement is updated as necessary to reflect current collection methods and usage of website visitor information. NEOMED reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement, effective when it is re-posted to the NEOMED website **,** so please check back regularly to keep informed of updates to this Policy. Your continued use of the website after any change in this Privacy Statement will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Contact Us

We are committed to working with you to address any complaint or concern about privacy. If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, please email [web@neomed.edu](mailto:web@neomed.edu).
